A Guide to the Washington Family Archives, 1779 - 1934
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Washington Family Archive 1779-1934
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 2006.4
1 box
Papers of members of the extended Washington family.
Washington family.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 2006.
Biographical/Historical Information
Descendents of George Washington's family.
Scope and Content
A collection of over 120 letters, documents, receipts, and envelopes relating to the extended family of George Washington.
Arrangement
The collection has been inventoried but not arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Bassett, George Washington.; Greenbaum, Daniel.; Lewis, Fielding.; Lewis, Henry H.; Mitchell, C.F.; Washington, Ella Bassett.
Family Names:
Washington family.; Bassett family.
Subjects:
Correspondence.
Geographical Names:
Baltimore (Md.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Receipts (financial records); Invoices
Collection Contents
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1881 - 1888 (Box 1)
  - Bassett, Lewis, and Washington Letters, 1779-1869 (Folder 1)
    - Fielding Lewis Sr. to Fielding Lewis Jr., 1779 September 15
    - 1826 May 1 (Aunt) Lewis to George Washington Bassett
    - 1832 February 27 GW Bassett to Francis Tali[?]ferro, Esq.
    - 1835 April 24 B. Bassett to GW Bassett
    - 180? December 7 Andrew Broaddus to John Bassett
    - 1833 July 3 Jacob ?? to GW Bassett
    - 1869 January 14 Charles Washington to Eleanor Washington
    - 1833 August 22 ? Johnson to unknown
    - 1856 August 28 Land deed: John A. and Eleanor Washington to David Dillon
    - 1821 October 15 J.W. Lewis (mother) to Betty Bassett (daughter)
    - 1803 March 14 Augustine Bougham to John Bassett
  - Bassett Letters, 1871-1876 (Folder 2)
    - 1882 February 20 GW Bassett to HH Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1886 August 8 GW Bassett to Cousin HH Lewis
    - 1886 March 18 E. Calvin Williams to Capt. H.H. Lewis
    - 1879 September 25 Receipt, B.B. Bassett and G.W. Bassett to O. Horowitz
    - 1885 September 4 G.W. Bassett to (cousin) Henry H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1881 March 30 G.W. Bassett to unknown
    - 1881 April 2 G.W. Bassett to unknown
    - 1883 July 7 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis
    - 1885 July 9 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis
    - 1885 July 2 E. Calvin Williams to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1881 May 17 R.L. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1881 December 9 R.L. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 188? November 17 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1882 November 10 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1885 October 22 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1886 January 30 G.W. Bassett to H.H. Lewis (with envelope)
    - 1871 December 5 (brother) to Mrs. L.W. Washington (with envelope)
  - Mitchell Family Letters, 1867-1934 (Folder 3)
    - 1867 March 13 C.F. Mitchell to (sister) Ella [Washington]
    - 1875 July 24 C.F. Mitchell to J. Bearsley
    - February 24 envelope to Mrs. E.B. Washington
    - 1892 January 24 C.F. Mitchell to Ella (Mrs. E.B. Washington, w/ envelope)
    - 1880 October 4 Check: B.B. Bassett to Daniel Greenbaum
    - 1934 May 15 Stock certificate: Virginia L. Mitchell, owner of 29 shares, Bonanza United Mines, Ltd., with envelope from 1941
    - 1874 February 23 C.F. Mitchell to Ella Washington (with envelope)
    - July 6 Fannie to (sister) Ella
    - 1875 April 26 C.F. Mitchell to Ella [Washington] (with envelope)
    - 1875 October 18 C.F. Mitchell to Ella [Washington] (with envelope)
    - 1875 May 7 C.F. Mitchell to Ella [Washington]
    - March 3 envelope to Mrs. E.B. Washington
  - Homeowner expenses, Baltimore, MD, 1880-1889 (Folder 4)
    - Copy of a receipt, 1884-1885
    - Bill for emptying sink 1888 May 1
    - Receipt for payment, 1888 June 6
    - Receipt for wallpapering, 1883 December 1
    - 1886 February 5 E. Calvin Williams to H.H. Lewis
    - Molasses recipe, undated
    - Receipt, 1888 May 19
    - Menu from meal on February 15, written on paper from The Breakers, year unknown
    - Receipt for carpentry, 1886 November 16
    - Receipt, repairs on 87 Patterson Ave, 1880 December 29
    - Receipt, 1881 January 11
    - Recipes, from 7 Carroll St., Portland, ME, date unknown
    - Water bill, Baltimore, 1887
    - Check: $60 to Daniel Greenbaum from Ella B. Washington
    - Bills for rent 87-89 Patterson Ave (6 items) 1880-1883
    - Bills for rent 87-89 Patterson Ave (5 items) 1886-1888
    - Promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum, 1882 October 4
    - G.W. Bassett account with B.F. Haines, 1881 January 5
    - Bill for plumber, 1886 April 6
    - Receipt for paving, 1883 November 17
    - Receipt for fence repair, 1884 April 16
    - Promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum (2 copies), 1884 October 4
    - Promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum (2 copies), 1880 October 4
    - Check: Henry H. Lewis to Daniel Greenbaum, 1890 October 4
    - Promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum, 1882 October 4
    - Statement (no year)
    - 1881 September 3 H.H. Lewis to Daniel Greenbaum
    - 1881 September 11 R.L. Bassett to H.H. Lewis
    - Plumber bill, 1886 May 20
    - Bill, B.J. Haines and J.W. Everist
    - Bill for paperhanging, 1880 July 20
    - Receipt, B.J. Haines to H.G. Moran, 1880 June 4
    - Statement, Papering one room, 1890 June 6
    - Balance, Mr. Lewis to A.J. G(??), 1882 December 16
    - Recipe, oatmeal wafers
    - Telegram (in envelope), R.J. Bassett to H.H. Lewis
    - Insurance bill, 1882 June 28
    - Letter fragment, no names no date
    - Bill for roof repair, 1880 July 10
    - Bill for painting, 1882 June 21
    - Receipt, home insurance, 1887 December 27
    - Water bill, Baltimore, 1889
    - Account, 1890 June 12
    - Repair bill, 1888 July 3
    - Check: $25, 1889 January 21
    - Receipt, 1885 September 18
    - Water bill, 87 Patterson, 1886
    - Water bill, 89 Patterson, 1886
    - Check, $25, 1881September 22
    - 1885 November 12 E. Calvin Williams to H.H. Lewis
    - Tax bills, 87-89 Patterson (3 items), 1885-1886
    - Receipt, $3.25 from H.H. Lewis, 1887 July 25
    - Bill, Hagger and Bennett, 188? August 1
    - Rent receipt, 1884 September 15
    - Bill, Francis Bibleheiser, 1881 December 31
    - Bill, Francis Bibleheiser, 1882 March
    - Bill, George W. Della Sink Emptying, 188? December 10
    - Bill, Philip March Sink Empyting, 1887 April 14
    - Insurance bill, J.S. Maury & Co., 1883 May 3
    - Water bill, 87-89 Patterson, 1879
    - Bill, Odorless Excavating Appartus Co., 1886 August 23
    - Bill, August Miller, 1890 April 26
    - Bill, hinges and bolt on cellar dome, 1883 August 18
    - Bill, B.F. Haines to J.H. Everist, 1880 January
    - Promise to pay Orville Horowitz, 1878 December 26
    - Recipe, Raised Corn Rolls
    - Bill, Capt. Lewis to Alfred High, 1890 September 17
    - Bill, Capt. Lewis to Alfred High, 1890 May 3
    - Receipt, $1.50 received by Strohm from Capt. H.H. Lewis
    - Bill, Lewis to Jas. A. Myers, 1889 June 8
    - Dinner menu, February 14
    - Recipe, on paper from the Hotel Clarendon
  - Letters: C. Mitchell to E. Washington, and others.1867-1881 (Folder 5)
    - 1875 May 10C. Mitchell to Ella Washington (with envelope)
    - 1874 December 18C. Mitchell to Ella Washington
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella Washington 1875 May 10
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella Washington 1874 December 18
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella Washington 1873 November 2
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella Washington 1867 January 20
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella Washington (with envelope) 1875 May 5
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella [Washington] (with envelope) 1871 December 9
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella [Washington] (with envelope) 1871 October 18
    - R.L. Bassett to Capt. H.H. Lewis (with envelope) 1881 September 12
    - Willoughby Newton, Jr. to Capt. H.H. Lewis (with envelope) 1881 November 19
    - Charles [Mitchell] to Ella [Washington] 1875 April 10
  - Ella Bassett Washington Letters and notes and mortgages for Mordington (Happy retreat) Clover Lea and other Washington homes., 1886-1890 (Folder 6)
    - Promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum, 1888 October 4
    - Receipt, $100 received by Ella Washington from H.H. Lewis, 1887 November 5
    - Receipt, $50 received by Ella Washington from H.H. Lewis, 1888 May 23
    - Ella Washington to Cousin
    - 1876 February 10[Landtrob] to Sir with envelope addressed to Ms. E.B. Washington
    - Undated, pencil letter from EBW
    - Introduction card, E.B. Washington introducing brother in law, C.F. Mitchell to John W. [Warrin], in envelope
    - Introuction card, E.B. Washington introducing C.F. Mitchell to Mr. G.A. Leavitz, in envelope
    - Check, $20, to Williams & Gibson from G.W. Bassett,, with “No Protest” slip.1883 April 7
    - Mortgage note, promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum, 1888 October 4
    - Mortgage note, promise to pay Daniel Greenbaum, 1886 October 4
    - Envelope addressed to Mrs. E.B. Washington
    - 1888 Sept 26 Henry H. Lewis to Ella B. Washington
    - [year] November 30from C. Mitchell
    - Receipt, check received by Ella B. Washington from Henry H. Lewis, 1890 July 14
  - Unlabeled (Folder 7)
    - Article of agreement
    - Deed (in two pieces), 1856 September 15
    - Dillon family land deeds (3 leaves)